<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Quizkart</string>
    <string name="a_computer_is_a_programmable_electronic_device_that_accepts_raw_data_as_input_and_processes_it_with_a_set_of_instructions_a_program_to_produce_the_result_as_output_it_renders_output_just_after_performing_mathematical_and_logical_operations_and_can_save_the_output_for_future_use_it_can_process_numerical_as_well_as_non_numerical_calculations_the_term_computer_is_derived_from_the_latin_word_computare_which_means_to_calculate_n_a_computer_is_designed_to_execute_applications_and_provides_a_variety_of_solutions_through_integrated_hardware_and_software_components_it_works_with_the_help_of_programs_and_represents_the_decimal_numbers_through_a_string_of_binary_digits_it_also_has_a_memory_that_stores_the_data_programs_and_result_of_processing_the_components_of_a_computer_such_as_machinery_that_includes_wires_transistors_circuits_hard_disk_are_called_hardware_whereas_the_programs_and_data_are_called_software_n_it_is_believed_that_the_analytical_engine_was_the_first_computer_which_was_invented_by_charles_babbage_in_1837_it_used_punch_cards_as_read_only_memory_charles_babbage_is_also_known_as_the_father_of_the_computer">A computer is a programmable electronic device that accepts raw data as input and processes it with a set of instructions (a program) to produce the result as output. It renders output just after performing mathematical and logical operations and can save the output for future use. It can process numerical as well as non-numerical calculations. The term computer is derived from the Latin word computare which means to calculate. \n A computer is designed to execute applications and provides a variety of solutions through integrated hardware and software components. It works with the help of programs and represents the decimal numbers through a string of binary digits. It also has a memory that stores the data, programs, and result of processing. The components of a computer such as machinery that includes wires, transistors, circuits, hard disk are called hardware. Whereas, the programs and data are called software. \n It is believed that the Analytical Engine was the first computer which was invented by Charles Babbage in 1837. It used punch cards as read-only memory. Charles Babbage is also known as the father of the computer.</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="drive_n_na_drive_is_a_location_medium_that_is_capable_of_storing_and_reading_information_that_is_not_easily_removed_like_a_disk_or_disc_all_drives_store_files_and_programs_used_by_your_computer_for_example_when_you_write_a_letter_in_a_word_processor_the_program_is_loaded_from_the_hard_drive_when_you_save_the_document_it_s_saved_to_the_hard_drive_or_other_disk_or_drive_n_ncompact_disc_cd_a_compact_disc_is_a_portable_storage_medium_that_can_be_used_to_record_store_and_play_back_audio_video_and_other_n_npen_drive_a_usb_flash_drive_also_known_as_a_usb_stick_usb_thumb_drive_or_pen_drive_is_a_plug_and_play_portable_storage_device_that_uses_flash_memory_and_is_lightweight_enough_to_attach_to_a_keychain_a_usb_flash_drive_can_be_used_in_place_of_a_compact_disc_a_usb_flash_drive_also_known_as_a_usb_stick_usb_thumb_drive_or_pen_drive_is_a_plug_and_play_portable_storage_device_that_uses_flash_memory_and_is_lightweight_enough_to_attach_to_a_keychain_a_usb_flash_drive_can_be_used_in_place_of_a_compact_disc_n_nsd_card_a_secure_digital_sd_card_is_a_tiny_flash_memory_card_designed_for_high_capacity_memory_and_various_portable_devices_such_as_car_navigation_systems_cellular_phones_e_books_pdas_smartphones_digital_cameras_music_players_digital_video_camcorders_and_personal_computers_n_n_hd_hard_drive_hd_is_an_initialism_used_for_hard_drive_although_you_may_also_see_it_written_as_hdd_for_hard_disk_drive_2_short_for_high_definition_hd_describes_a_standard_of_digital_video_or_audio_for_video_it_means_1280_x_720_pixels_or_720p_on_televisions_n_ndigital_versatile_drive_short_for_digital_versatile_disc_or_digital_video_disc_a_dvd_or_dvd_rom_is_a_disc_capable_of_storing_a_significant_amount_more_data_than_a_standard_compact_disc_dvd_dvds_are_widely_used_for_storing_and_viewing_movies_and_other_data_n_ndvd_digital_video_disc_dvd_digital_video_disc_is_a_technology_based_on_optical_data_storage_similar_to_compact_disc_cd_optical_data_storage_is_a_method_of_storing_digital_information_1_s_and_0_s_by_using_light_to_read_the_information_n_n_n_n_n_n_n_n">DRIVE:-  \n  \nA drive is a location (medium) that is capable of storing and reading information that is not easily removed, like a disk or disc. All drives store files and programs used by your computer. For example, when you write a letter in a word processor, the program is loaded from the hard drive. When you save the document, it\'s saved to the hard drive or other disk or drive. \n \nCompact disc (CD) = A compact disc is a portable storage medium that can be used to record, store and play back audio, video and other. \n \nPen Drive = A USB flash drive -- also known as a USB stick, USB thumb drive or pen drive -- is a plug-and-play portable storage device that uses flash memory and is lightweight enough to attach to a keychain. A USB flash drive can be used in place of a compact disc.A USB flash drive -- also known as a USB stick, USB thumb drive or pen drive -- is a plug-and-play portable storage device that uses flash memory and is lightweight enough to attach to a keychain. A USB flash drive can be used in place of a compact disc. \n \nSD Card = A Secure Digital (SD) card is a tiny flash memory card designed for high-capacity memory and various portable devices, such as car navigation systems, cellular phones, e-books, PDAs, smartphones, digital cameras, music players, digital video camcorders and personal computers. \n \n HD Hard Drive = HD is an initialism used for hard drive, although you may also see it written as HDD for hard disk drive. 2. Short for high definition, HD describes a standard of digital video or audio. For video, it means 1280 x 720 pixels, or 720p on televisions. \n \nDigital Versatile Drive = Short for digital versatile disc or digital video disc, a DVD or DVD-ROM is a disc capable of storing a significant amount more data than a standard compact disc. DVD = DVDs are widely used for storing and viewing movies and other data. \n \nDVD (digital video disc) = DVD (digital video disc) is a technology based on optical data storage similar to compact disc (CD). Optical data storage is a method of storing digital information (1\'s and 0\'s) by using light to read the information. \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="about_computer_n_na_computer_is_a_programmable_electronic_device_that_accepts_raw_data_as_input_and_processes_it_with_a_set_of_instructions_a_program_to_produce_the_result_as_output_it_renders_output_just_after_performing_mathematical_and_logical_operations_and_can_save_the_output_for_future_use_it_can_process_numerical_as_well_as_non_numerical_calculations_the_term_computer_is_derived_from_the_latin_word_computare_which_means_to_calculate_a_computer_is_designed_to_execute_applications_and_provides_a_variety_of_solutions_through_integrated_hardware_and_software_components_it_works_with_the_help_of_programs_and_represents_the_decimal_numbers_through_a_string_of_binary_digits_it_also_has_a_memory_that_stores_the_data_programs_and_result_of_processing_the_components_of_a_computer_such_as_machinery_that_includes_wires_transistors_circuits_hard_disk_are_called_hardware_whereas_the_programs_and_data_are_called_software_it_is_believed_that_the_analytical_engine_was_the_first_computer_which_was_invented_by_charles_babbage_in_1837_it_used_punch_cards_as_read_only_memory_charles_babbage_is_also_known_as_the_father_of_the_computer_n_n_n_n_n_n_n_n">ABOUT COMPUTER:- \n  \nA computer is a programmable electronic device that accepts raw data as input and processes it with a set of instructions (a program) to produce the result as output. It renders output just after performing mathematical and logical operations and can save the output for future use. It can process numerical as well as non-numerical calculations. The term computer is derived from the Latin word computare which means to calculate. A computer is designed to execute applications and provides a variety of solutions through integrated hardware and software components. It works with the help of programs and represents the decimal numbers through a string of binary digits. It also has a memory that stores the data, programs, and result of processing. The components of a computer such as machinery that includes wires, transistors, circuits, hard disk are called hardware. Whereas, the programs and data are called software. It is believed that the Analytical Engine was the first computer which was invented by Charles Babbage in 1837. It used punch cards as read-only memory. Charles Babbage is also known as the father of the computer. \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="drive">DRIVE:-  \n  \nA drive is a location (medium) that is capable of storing and reading information that is not easily removed, like a disk or disc. All drives store files and programs used by your computer. For example, when you write a letter in a word processor, the program is loaded from the hard drive. When you save the document, it\'s saved to the hard drive or other disk or drive. \n \nCompact disc (CD) = A compact disc is a portable storage medium that can be used to record, store and play back audio, video and other. \n \nPen Drive = A USB flash drive — also known as a USB stick, USB thumb drive or pen drive — is a plug-and-play portable storage device that uses flash memory and is lightweight enough to attach to a keychain. A USB flash drive can be used in place of a compact disc.A USB flash drive -- also known as a USB stick, USB thumb drive or pen drive -- is a plug-and-play portable storage device that uses flash memory and is lightweight enough to attach to a keychain. A USB flash drive can be used in place of a compact disc. \n \nSD Card = A Secure Digital (SD) card is a tiny flash memory card designed for high-capacity memory and various portable devices, such as car navigation systems, cellular phones, e-books, PDAs, smartphones, digital cameras, music players, digital video camcorders and personal computers. \n \n HD Hard Drive = HD is an initialism used for hard drive, although you may also see it written as HDD for hard disk drive. 2. Short for high definition, HD describes a standard of digital video or audio. For video, it means 1280 x 720 pixels, or 720p on televisions. \n \nDigital Versatile Drive = Short for digital versatile disc or digital video disc, a DVD or DVD-ROM is a disc capable of storing a significant amount more data than a standard compact disc. DVD = DVDs are widely used for storing and viewing movies and other data. \n \nDVD (digital video disc) = DVD (digital video disc) is a technology based on optical data storage similar to compact disc (CD). Optical data storage is a method of storing digital information (1\'s and 0\'s) by using light to read the information. \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="about">ABOUT COMPUTER:- \n  \nA computer is a programmable electronic device that accepts raw data as input and processes it with a set of instructions (a program) to produce the result as output. It renders output just after performing mathematical and logical operations and can save the output for future use. It can process numerical as well as non-numerical calculations. The term computer is derived from the Latin word computare which means to calculate. A computer is designed to execute applications and provides a variety of solutions through integrated hardware and software components. It works with the help of programs and represents the decimal numbers through a string of binary digits. It also has a memory that stores the data, programs, and result of processing. The components of a computer such as machinery that includes wires, transistors, circuits, hard disk are called hardware. Whereas, the programs and data are called software. It is believed that the Analytical Engine was the first computer which was invented by Charles Babbage in 1837. It used punch cards as read-only memory. Charles Babbage is also known as the father of the computer. \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="HARDWARE">HARDWARE/SOFTWARE:- \n  \n Computer Hardware: Hardware refers to the physical components of a computer. Computer Hardware is any part of the computer that we can touch these parts. These are the primary electronic devices used to build up the computer. Examples of hardware in a computer are the Processor, Memory Devices, Monitor, Printer, Keyboard, Mouse, and the Central Processing Unit. \n \nComputer Software: Software is a collection of instructions, procedures, and documentation that performs different tasks on a computer system. we can say also Computer Software is a programming code executed on a computer processor. The code can be machine-level code or the code written for an operating system. Examples of software are Ms Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Google Chrome, Photoshop, MySQL, etc.  \n  \n  \n \n  \n  \n  \n  \n \n</string>
    <string name="fullform">FULL FORMS:-  \n \nRAM= Random Access Memory Read Only Memory  \nCPU=Central Processing Unit  \nURL= Uniform Resource Locator  \nUSB= nUniversal Serial Bus  \nUPS= Uninterruptible Power Supply  \nCD= Compact Disc  \nDVD= Digital Versatile Disc  \nIP= Internet Protocol  \nGPU= Graphics Processing Unit  \nGMAIL= Graphical Mail  \nPING= Packet InterNet Groper  \nLAN= Local Area Network PAN Personal Area Network  \nALU= Arithmetic Logical Unit  \nPCM= Pulse-Code Modulation VPN  \n Virtual Private Network  \nZIP= Zig-zag In-line Package  \nVFS= Virtual File System  \nIPC= Inter-Process Communication  \nWIFI= Wireless Fidelity  \nPTP= Picture Transfer Protocol  \nHHD= Hybrid Hard Drive  \nURI= Uniform Resource Identifier  \nSRAM= Static Random-Access Memory  \nVRAM= Video Random Access MemoryDVD  \nDVD= Digital Video Disc  \nCD-ROM= Compact Disk-Read Only Memory  \nWWW= World Wide Web  \nFTP= File Transfer Protocol  \nP2P= Peer-To-Peer  \nVAN= Value-Added Network  \nPOST= Power on self-test  \nHDD= Hard Disk Drive  \nIOS= Internets Operating System  \nFDD= Floppy Disk Drive  \nSVG= Scalable Vector Graphics  \nVDU= video display unit  \nWWW= World Wide Web  \nGUI= Graphical user interface  \nCAD= Computer-aided design  \nCU= control uni  \nhttp= HyperText Transfer Protocol  \nIPO= Input–process–output  \nISP= Internet service provider  \nDVR= Digital Vedio Recorder \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="keyboart_mouse">KEYBOARD-MOUSE:- \n  \n Keyboard and mouse basics Being able to use a keyboard and mouse is an important part of using a desktop computer or laptop and you\'ll find helpful tips below to get you started and where to get help. \n Using a keyboard Whenever you use a desktop computer or laptop, you’ll probably use a keyboard. The most common kind is called a ‘QWERTY’ keyboard. QWERTY describes the top row of letters on the keyboard. \n What a keyboard looks like ? \n A keyboard is for putting information including letters, words and numbers into your computer. You press the individual buttons on the keyboard when you type. \n The number keys across the top of the keyboard are also found on the right of the keyboard. \n The letter keys are in the centre of the keyboard. \n The symbol keys to the right of the letters include symbols such as the question mark and full stop. \n The keys that surround the letters, numbers and symbol keys on the left, right and bottom of the keyboard help you to choose where and how you type. \n \n Using the keys \n When you open a document or click in a box to type, you will see a vertical flashing line. This is the cursor, it shows you where you are about to start typing on a page or screen. \n  \n Pressing the \'shift\' key allows you to type capital letters and the symbols at the top of the keys. \n  \n The \'shift\' keys are on the left and right of the keyboard, with the arrow pointing upwards. \n  \n For capital letters, hold down the \'shift\' key and hold and type the letter. \n  \n For symbols at the top of a number key, press down the symbol key and then type the symbol. You can use the \'shift\' key to type any symbol at the top of a key. \n  \n The \'caps lock\' key allows you to write in capital letters. To turn it on, press it once and type. To turn it off, press it again. \n  \n Putting in spaces, moving your cursor and deleting text The \'space bar\' puts a space between words. Press it once to put in a space. \n  \n The \'tab\' key puts a bigger space between words. Press it once to put in a space. \n  \n The \'enter\' key moves your cursor down a line. \n  \n The \'arrow\' keys allow you to move your cursor in all directions on the page or screen - up, down, left and right. \n  \n To delete your typing you need to put your cursor to the right of a word. Press the \'backspace\' button to delete your word. The cursor will move to the left and delete as it goes. \n  \n Using a mouse \n  \n There are lots of different styles of mouse, but most have a left and a right button. \n illustration of left and right click of computer mouse To hold your mouse, rest your hand over it and put your index finger on the left button and your thumb resting on the side. The cable needs to be pointing towards the computer. The mouse needs to always be in contact with a mouse mat, desk or hard surface. You use your mouse to move the cursor around the screen. The cursor changes, depending on what you are doing on the computer. As an arrow you use it for moving and selecting things, as a hand for clicking on links when you are on the internet and it becomes an hourglass when you are waiting for the computer to do something. \n Single clicking You single click with the left mouse button to select things. Just quickly left click and then let go of the button.  \n Double clicking You double click with the left mouse button to open things, such as a folder. You need to double click quickly, think about the ‘knock, knock’ you do on a door.  \n \n Drag and drop Drag and drop is when you move something from one place to another.  \n  \n First select the item with the left mouse button and keep the button pressed down. Then move the mouse and the item on screen will move with the cursor. When you have the cursor and item in the position you want, release the left mouse button. \n  \n The item will now be dropped to where the cursor is positioned on the screen. \n  \n You use drag and drop to move things around your computer, such as files between folders. \n  \n Right button \n If you ever accidentally click the right mouse button, a list of computer commands will appear. To remove the list just move the mouse and single click the left button. \n  \n Laptop trackpad or touchpad \n \n Laptops can have a built in mouse within the keyboard. This is operated by finger touch. This specialised surface is used instead of a mouse and needs only very short finger movements to move the cursor across the display screen.  \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="bitbyte">BIT-BYTE-NIBBLE:- \n  \nBits and Bytes by the Numbers Every byte consists of eight bits. So, you’d think that a kilobyte would be 1,000 bytes, right? Not exactly. Remember, computers operate using the binary system. That means hard drives, memory, and bandwidth are measured in powers of two. Going back to the kilobyte example: 2 ^ 10 equals 1,024, not 1,000. \n Confused? Let’s explain it by using an example you’d encounter in day-to-day computing: an IP address. \n An IP address in Internet Protocol (IP) consists of 32 bits (or four bytes). For example, the IP address 192.168.1.1 has values of 192, 168, 1, and 1 for each of its bytes. The encoding of that IP address in bits looks like this: \n \n 11000000 10101000 00000001 000000001 This means that: \n  \n192 = 1100000 \n 168 = 1010100 \n 1 = 00000001 \n \n Converting Bits to Bytes (and Beyond) \n Let’s go down the data rabbit hole even more with this conversion table: \n  \n 8 bits = 1 byte \n 1,024 bytes = kilobyte \n 1,024 kilobytes = megabyte \n 1,024 megabytes = gigabyte \n 1,024 gigabytes = terabyte \n 1nibble =4 bit \n \n As you can see, that 1,024 number keeps popping up! Say you were to convert 4 kilobytes into bits. You’d first convert kilobytes to bytes (4 x 1,024). Next, you’d use that total (4,096) to convert to bits (8 x 4,096) to get 32,768 bits. \n These numbers lead to confusion among consumers. For example, when you purchase a 1 terabyte hard drive, it has about 8 trillion bits. Why “about” 8 trillion? Well, manufacturers are assuming a rounded 1000 megabytes per gigabyte, while computers use 1,024. \n This difference in numbers means when you purchase a 1 terabyte hard drive, you’ll notice about 35 gigs aren’t available. On top of this, your operating system needs a small amount of space on the disk. \n Even with all this information, computing can still be confusing. The beauty of computing is that it is a structured system with static rules. \n Technology always advances, but the principles stay the same. Also, if a computer isn’t working, trust us, it’s going to let you know. \n \n A nibble has 16 potential values thanks to its four bits, which is the same as one hexadecimal digit. As a result, a nybble is also known as a “hex digit”. Because of the four bits that make up each nybble, nybbles are also referred to as “quadbits” in data transfers. \n  \n 1 Nibble = 4 Bits \n 1 nibble = 0.5 Bytes \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="back_to_home">Back TO home</string>
    <string name="retry_quiz">RETRY QUIZ</string>
    <string name="congratulation">Congratulation</string>
    <string name="you_did_a_great_job_nin_the_quiz">You did a great job \nin the quiz</string>
    <string name="score">Score</string>
    <string name="_0">0</string>
    <string name="what_is_computer">What is Computer</string>
    <string name="bird">Bird</string>
    <string name="go_to_intermediate">GO TO INTERMEDIATE</string>
    <string name="about_computer">About Computer</string>
    <string name="drived">Drive</string>
    <string name="bit_byte_nibble">BIT-BYTE-NIBBLE</string>
    <string name="full_forms">Full Forms</string>
    <string name="hardware_software">Hardware/Software</string>
    <string name="cpu_monitor">CPU-MONITOR</string>
    <string name="keyboard_mouse">KEYBOARD-MOUSE</string>
    <string name="go_to_advance">GO TO ADVANCE</string>
    <string name="learn">LEARN</string>
    <string name="quiz">QUIZ</string>
    <string name="learn_with_quizkart">Learn With Quizkart</string>
    <string name="get_started">Get Started</string>
    <string name="tzar_rival">tzar Rival</string>
    <string name="beginner">BEGINNER</string>
    <string name="intermediate">INTERMEDIATE</string>
    <string name="advance">ADVANCE</string>
    <string name="cpu_monitor_n_ncentral_processing_unit_cpu_n_n_the_cpu_or_central_processing_unit_is_basically_like_the_brain_of_computer_systems_it_processes_all_the_information_on_a_computational_level_central_processing_unit_cpu_the_cpu_or_central_processing_unit_is_basically_like_the_brain_of_computer_systems_it_processes_all_the_information_on_a_computational_level_it_takes_all_the_processes_from_the_ram_and_processes_it_to_perform_the_tasks_required_by_the_computer_system_the_central_processing_unit_is_usually_seated_in_a_socket_that_utilizes_a_lever_or_a_latch_with_a_hinged_plate_with_a_cut_out_in_the_center_to_secure_the_central_processing_unit_onto_the_motherboard_it_has_many_copper_pads_underneath_it_for_the_socket_contacts_to_push_up_against_them_to_make_electrical_contact_there_are_other_ways_cpus_can_be_attached_to_the_motherboard_n_nmonitor_or_visual_display_unit_vdu_n_n_a_monitor_is_an_output_device_used_to_visualize_the_graphics_data_sent_from_the_computer_s_gpu_there_are_various_types_of_monitors_on_the_market_a_led_light_emitting_diode_backlit_lcd_liquid_crystal_display_monitor_is_the_most_commonly_used_with_modern_computers_there_are_also_various_computer_screen_sizes_with_different_aspect_ratios_the_aspect_ratio_is_simply_the_ratio_between_height_and_width_for_example_a_16_9_aspect_ratio_computer_screen_will_have_16_parts_wide_to_9_parts_in_height_there_are_also_curved_monitors_but_they_are_more_expensive_computer_screens_monitors_also_have_a_fast_response_time_to_keep_up_with_the_high_demands_required_to_eliminate_delays_with_user_input_for_gaming_n_n_n_n_n_n_n_n_n_n">CPU-MONITOR:- \n  \nCentral Processing Unit (CPU):-  \n  \n=The CPU or central processing unit is basically like the brain of computer systems. It processes all the information on a computational level. Central Processing Unit (CPU)The CPU or central processing unit is basically like the brain of computer systems. It processes all the information on a computational level. It takes all the processes from the RAM and processes it to perform the tasks required by the computer system. The central processing unit is usually seated in a socket that utilizes a lever or a latch with a hinged plate with a cut out in the center to secure the central processing unit onto the motherboard. It has many copper pads underneath it for the socket contacts to push up against them to make electrical contact.There are other ways CPUs can be attached to the motherboard. \n \nMonitor or Visual Display Unit (VDU):- \n \n=A monitor is an output device used to visualize the graphics data sent from the computer’s GPU.There are various types of monitors on the market. A LED (Light Emitting Diode) backlit LCD (Liquid Crystal Display) monitor is the most commonly used with modern computers. There are also various computer screen sizes with different aspect ratios. The aspect ratio is simply the ratio between height and width. For example, a 16:9 aspect ratio computer screen will have 16 parts wide to 9 parts in height. There are also curved monitors, but they are more expensive computer screens. Monitors also have a fast response time to keep up with the high demands required to eliminate delays with user input for gaming.  \n  \n \n  \n \n  \n \n  \n \n  \n</string>
</resources>